Inventory of the Božidar Puric Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Božidar Puric Papers
1891-1980
82038
Hoover Institution Archives
15 manuscript boxes, 10 oversize boxes, 1 oversize folder (12.6 linear feet)
Writings, correspondence, diaries, reports, press releases, bulletins, clippings, pamphlets, and photographs, relating to pre-World War II Yugoslav diplomacy, resistance movements in Yugoslavia during the war, diplomatic activities of the Yugoslav government-in-exile, and postwar Serbian émigré affairs. Includes photographs of Serbian military activities during the Balkan Wars of 1912-1913. Also available on microfilm (22 reels).
Puric, Božidar, 1891-1977
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1982.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Related Materials
Milan Gavrilovic papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Konstantin Fotic papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Biographical Note
1891 Born, Belgrade, Serbia
1912 Graduated from the Faculty of Law in Paris, France
1916 Appointed clerk of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of the Yugoslav government-in-exile on Corfu, Greece
1918 Doctoral thesis completed, Casuala rebus sic stantibus en droit international public
1918-1919 Secretary of the Legation of the Kingdom of Serbs, Croats and Slovenes in Washington, D.C.
1919-1920 Chargé d'Affaires of the Kingdom of Yugoslavia in Vladivostok, Russia
1920-1922 Consul in San Francisco, California
1922-1926 Consul in Chicago, Illinois
1927 Head of Political Department, Ministry of Foreign Affairs
1928-1929 Chargé d'Affaires of the Kingdom of Yugoslavia in Washington, D.C.
1929-1932 Counsellor of Legation in London, Great Britain
1932-1935 Under-Secretary for Foreign Affairs
1935-1940 Envoy and Minister Plenipotentiary in Paris, France
August 1943-July 1944 Prime Minster and Minister of Foreign Affairs, London, Great Britain
1977 Died in Chicago, Illinois
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection contains writings, correspondence, diaries, dispatches, reports, press releases, bulletins, clippings, pamphlets, and photographs relating to pre-World War II Yugoslav diplomacy, resistance movements in Yugoslavia during the war, diplomatic activities of the Yugoslav government-in-exile, and postwar Serbian émigré affairs. It includes photographs of Serbian military activities during the Balkan Wars of 1912-1913.
The Correspondence includes exchanges of letters with Royal Yugoslav government-in-exile political figures, individuals active in the Serbian and Yugoslavian émigré community, and family members. The correspondence reveals Puric's engagement in Serbian and Yugoslav émigré postwar politics. The Speeches and writings include a draft memoir, articles, and speeches written by Puric addressing the political situation and development in Yugoslavia prior to and during World War II. Speeches and writings by others cover topics such as the Communist Party role in Yugoslavia, partisan conflict, and views on the New Yugoslavia and Tito's politics.
The Nikola Pašic material consists of a report, speech, and notes documenting Pašic's political and diplomatic career as prime minister of the Kingdom of Serbia and the Kingdom of Serbs, Croats, and Slovenes, as well as a leader of the People's Radical Party in Serbia.
The Royal Yugoslav government office files are comprised of diplomatic correspondence and reports documenting the Royal Yugoslav government's foreign affairs and politics. Material on treaties and agreements provides an insider's view on diplomatic activities among European countries and the Balkan region in the period between 1927 and 1935. A considerable volume of material documents the Royal Yugoslav government-in-exile's political role during World War II, providing detail on the support of Yugoslav resistance movements and influence upon the creation of New Yugoslavia by the British government and other Allied countries.
Materials in the Draža Mihailović files include original telegrams and daily reports exchanged by the government-in-exile and Draža Mihailović. They detail the situation in Yugoslavia and document the government-in-exile's political and financial involvement in Mihailović's resistance movement.
The Serbian émigré affairs materials document the political engagement and aspirations of the Yugoslav émigré organizations to define the Royal Yugoslav government-in-exile's role in the creation of New Yugoslavia after World War II. The Printed Matter consists of newspapers, journals, clippings and other materials providing information on political developments in Yugoslavia and Europe at the end of World War II, and Yugoslav émigré community reflection on the political and economic condition in postwar Yugoslavia.
The Photographs are comprised of images depicting family members and Puric's official and social gatherings; included are prints documenting the visits of Petar II, King of Yugoslavia to Slovenia. The Oversize materials contain albums that include photographs, certificates, and other materials documenting official and social engagements. Of particular interest are albums containing photographs of the Balkan Wars of 1912 and 1913 depicting Serbian soldiers resting and preparing for the battle.
Access
Also available on microfilm (22 reels).
Balkan Peninsula--History--War of 1912-1913--Pictorial works.; Diplomats--Yugoslavia.; France--Foreign relations--Yugoslavia.; Pictorial works.; Serbia--Emigration and immigration.; Serbia--History.; World War, 1939-1945--Diplomatic history.; World War, 1939-1945--Governments in exile.; World War, 1939-1945--Underground movements.; World War, 1939-1945--Yugoslavia.; Yugoslavia--Foreign relations--1918-1945.; Yugoslavia--Foreign relations--France.; Yugoslavia--History--Axis occupation, 1941-1945.
- Biographical file, 1901-1979 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Contains certificates, a diary, address books, business cards, notes, a watercolor, and documents of Puric's wife, Dara Puric.
  Arrangement note
  Arranged by form
  - Personal documents, 1901-1960 (Folder 1: 1)
  - Address-telephone books with enclosures, business cards, and notes, circa 1920-1979 (Folder 1: 2-6)
  - Diary, 1944 (Folder 1: 7)
  - Holograph notes by Puric's wife, Dara Puric, 1979 and undated (Folder 1: 8)
  - Business cards and notes, undated (Folder 1: 9)
  - Watercolor, undated (Folder 1: 10)
- Correspondence, 1920-1980 (Box 2-4)
  Includes letters, postcards, and enclosures.
  Arranged in two groups, general and family, thereunder chronologically
  - General (Folder 2-4)
    - 1920-1923 (Folder 2: 1-4)
    - 1926-1930 (Folder 2: 5-9)
    - 1933-1934 (Folder 2: 10-11)
    - 1936-1953 (Folder 2: 12-29)
    - 1955-1960 (Folder 2: 30-36)
    - 1961-1963 (Folder 2: 37-39)
    - 1963-1975 (Folder 3: 1-16)
    - 1976-1977 (Folder 4: 1-2)
    - 1980 (Folder 4: 3)
    - Undated (Folder 4: 4-5)
  - Family correspondence, undated (Folder 4: 6)
- Speeches and writings, 1907-1963 (Box 4)
  Consists of articles, memoir drafts, notes, and speeches by Puric.
  Arranged in groups by format, then alphabetically by title
  - Writings, 1907-1946, and undated (Folder 4)
    - "Apizment," typescript, undated (Folder 4: 7)
    - "Blaženi i Blaženstva Protojerija i profesora Dimitrija Najdanovic," typescript, undated (Folder 4: 8)
    - "Crkva i Narodnost," typescript, undated (Folder 4: 9)
    - "Deveti Octobar 1934," Beli Orao, October 1934 (Folder 4: 10)
    - Memoir draft, holograph, including enclosure, circa 1946 (Folder 4: 11-13)
    - "Ko je i kako doveo Tita i Komuniste na vlast u Jugoslaviji," typescript, undated (Folder 4: 14)
    - Poem, holograph, 1907, 1908, undated (Folder 4: 15)
    - "Vidovdan," typescript, undated (Folder 4: 16)
    - "Vidovdanska nadahnuca," typescript, undated (Folder 4: 17)
    - "Churchill Winston," typescript, undated (Folder 4: 18)
    - "The Yugoslav Basic Handbook,", June 1944 (Folder 4: 19)
    - Untitled fragments, typescripts and holograph. Includes enclosures, undated (Folder 4: 20-22)
    - Notes, undated, typescript and holographs (Folder 4: 23)
  - Speeches, 1937, 1963, and undated (Folder 4)
    - Address to students at Petit Lycée Janson-de-Sailly, Paris, 1937 (Folder 4: 24)
    - Addresses, 1963, undated (Folder 4: 25)
      - Vaši Preosveštenstva, casni Oci, April 1963 (Folder 4: 25)
      - "Dragi gospodnine Milisavljevic,", undated (Folder 4: 25)
      - "Politika i Moral,", undated (Folder 4: 25)
      - "Pretsednice i brate Milutine Bajcetic, sveto sveštenstvo..," speech at Congress of Serbian National Defense (SNO) Canada, undated (Folder 4: 25)
- Speeches and writings by others, 1944-1969 (Box 5)
  Consists of articles, typescripts, and speeches by others.
  Arranged by format, then alphabetically by title
  - Writings, 1941-1969 (Folder 5)
    - Cedo Mamula, untitled, typescript, U.S.A., 1956 (Folder 5: 1)
    - Dragan Ilic, "Povodom knjige na strašnom sudu," typescript, 1968 (Folder 5: 2)
    - Dragiša Vasic, "Albanija," typescript, undated (Folder 5: 3)
    - J. Ðonovic, "Yugoslav Tragedy," typescript, undated (Folder 5: 4-5)
    - Milan Doychinovich, Amanet, Nica, France, 1969 (Folder 5: 6)
    - Milan Petrovic, "Moj Književni Kriticar" poem, undated (Folder 5: 7)
    - Sinša Stankovic, "Narodono oslobidilacki front-jedinstven primer u istoriji Južnih Slovena," Politika, 31 October 1944 (Folder 5: 8)
    - Slobodan Draškvic, "Srpski Narod i Srpska Politika," typescript, 1947 (Folder 5: 9)
    - Svetozar Petrovic Krajinski, "Jugosavija izmedu dva rata," 1960, Oslo, Sweden (Folder 5: 10)
    - Vojvoda Momcilo Ðulic, "Poverljivo pismo najužim saradnicam," typescript, June 1958 (Folder 5: 11)
    - Unknown authors (Folder 5)
      - "Report of a Partisan Captain Given to the Yugoslav H. Q. Concerning to Partisan Movement in Yugoslavia,", June 1944 (Folder 4: 12)
      - "Srbine, Brate, Pacenice, Mucenice," typescript, undated (Folder 4: 13)
  - Speeches, 1951 and undated (Folder 5)
    - Brank Pekic, "Mobla i ?alba Branka Pekica," speech at the Serb National Federation convention in Detroit, 1951 (Folder 5: 14)
    - Unknown author, "Draga braco i sestre, širom celog sveta,", undated (Folder 5: 15)
- Nikola Pašic materials, 1891-1957 and undated (Box 5)
  Contains a certificate, report, obituary, speech, printed matter, and a photograph documenting Nikola Pašic's political career as prime minister of Serbia and Yugoslavia.
  Arranged chronologically
  - Pašicevi Milioni, holograph notes, circa 1891 (Folder 5: 16)
    Assumed to be written by Nikola Pašic
  - Tapija, land registry certificates, 1891 and 1907 (Folder 2: 17)
  - Correspondence, 1907 (Folder 2: 18)
  - Paris Peace Conference report holograph, 1919 (Folder 2: 19)
  - Pašic, Ilustrovani Radikalni Almanh, 1925 (Folder 2: 20)
  - Sopmenica Nikole Pašica, 1926 (Folder 2: 21)
  - "Nacionalna Politika Nikola Pašica," Politika, January 1956 (Folder 2: 22)
    Includes the original typescript by Božidar Puric
  - "In Memory of Nikola Pašic," typescript and clippings, 1926-1957, and undated (Folder 2: 23)
  - "Gospodo Poslanici," speech by Nikola Pašic, undated (Folder 2: 24)
  - Photograph of Alexandar I of Yugoslavia and Nikola Pašic with an unidentified man, print reproduction, undated (Folder 2: 25)
- Royal Yugoslav government office files, 1915-1947 (Box 5-11)
  Includes government documents, reports, memoranda, financial records, clippings, news releases, broadcast summaries, treaties, and agreements received or sent from offices in Siberia, Belgrade, Paris, London, and Cairo, relating to Yugoslav foreign affairs and political situations prior to and during World War II.
  Arranged chronologically by office served, then by form or title
  - Siberia, Russia, 1915-1920 (Folder 5-6)
    - Diary, circa 1915 (Folder 5: 26)
    - Jugosloveni u Rusiji, report and notes, February 1917 (Folder 5: 27)
    - "Zapisnik," the Royal Yugoslav Military Officers, meetings minutes from Omsk, Russia, holograph, January 1919 (Folder 5: 28)
    - Royal Legation of Serbs, Croats, and Slovenes in Russia reports, February-August 1920 (Folder 5: 29)
    - Ataman Semenov, undated (Folder 6: 1)
  - Belgrade, Yugoslavia, Ministry of Foreign Affairs office, 1927-1935 (Folder 6)
    - Treaties, agreements, and reports, 1927-1935 (Folder 6)
      - "Traité d'Alliance Défensive entre l'Albanie et l'Italie" Tirana, 22 November 1927 (Folder 6: 2)
      - Yugoslavia-France treaty renewal, 1932 (Folder 6: 3)
      - "Projet de Pacte d'Entente et de Collaboration, entre les puissances d'Europe membres permanents du Conseil de la S.D.N.,", 11 December 1932 (Folder 6: 4)
      - "Engleska Vlada i Conferencija u Streza," report, 1932 (Folder 6: 5)
      - Agreement of understanding and co-operation between France, Germany, Italy, and the United Britain, London, 7 June 1933 (Folder 6: 6)
      - Pacte d'entente et de collaboration paraphé à Rome le 7 Juin 1933, Paris (Folder 6: 7)
      - Ratification of "Pakt o organizaciji Mala Antanta, izmedu Jugoslavija-Cehoslovacka i Rumunija," Geneva, 16 February 1933 (Folder 6: 8)
      - "Traité d'amitié, de non-agression, de règlement judicaire, d'arbitrage et de conciliation entre Le Royaume de Yougoslavie et la République Turque,", 1933 (Folder 6: 9)
      - "Tripartitni Politicki Protokol," pact between Italy, Austria and Hungary, Rome, March 1934 (Folder 6: 10)
      - Procès-Verbal, 1934 (Folder 6: 11)
        Minutes of the third regular session of the board of the Balkan agreement between Romania and Bulgaria, Zagreb, 22 January 1934
  - Paris, France, Embassy office files, 1923-1941 (Folder 6-7)
    - Telegrams, reports, 1938-1941 (Folder 6-7)
      - January 1938-December 1939 (Folder 6: 12-22)
      - 1939 (Folder 7: 1-2)
      - January 1940-June 1941 (Folder 7: 3-14)
    - Office directory, undated (Folder 7: 15)
    - Clippings, 1923, 1936-1939 (Folder 7: 16)
  - London and Cairo, Prime Minister's office files, 1923-1947 (Folder 7-8)
    - Reports, memoranda, regulations, amendments, and clippings, 1942-1946 (Folder 7-8)
      - "Izveštaj o Kairskoj aferi u redovima naše vojske,", 1942-1943 (Folder 7: 17)
      - "Skidanje internacije, predigra za stupanje, i izlazak is engleske vojske,", 1943 (Folder 8: 1)
      - "Rešenje Kairske krize,", 1943 (Folder 8: 2)
      - "Plitvicka Deklaracija,", 1943 (Folder 8: 3)
      - "?oštaric-Pisacic" by A. Eugen, 1943 (Folder 8: 4)
      - "Kriza državnog jedinstava," memorandum addressed to Radivoj L. Kneževic, a Minister of the King Royal Yugoslavia Palace, 1943 (Folder 8: 5)
      - Miloš Trifunovic resignation letter, August 1943 (Folder 8: 6)
      - "Konferencija Saveznickih Ministara inostranih poslova sa A. Eden,", 1943 (Folder 8: 7)
      - Juraj Krnjevic's response to the editor Nineteenth Century and After, 1943 (Folder 8: 8)
      - "Pitanje budzeta Bana Hrvatske Banovine,", 1943 (Folder 8: 9)
      - Tihomir Panic's response to Mr. Bicanic's comments on "The National Bank and Its Nationalisation,", undated (Folder 8: 10)
      - Teheran Conference, December 1943 (Folder 8: 11)
      - "Jugoslovenska vojska u otadžbini, Hrvati i Domobrani,", 1944 (Folder 8: 12)
      - "Stanje u Crnoj Gori,", 1944 (Folder 8: 13)
      - Churchill's speech on the situation in Yugoslavia, report and clippings, 1944 (Folder 8: 14)
      - Konstatin Fotic's comments on "The Declaration of the Yugoslav Government in Cairo Concerning the Forming of So Called Communist Government in Yugoslavia,", 1943-1944 (Folder 8: 15)
      - Petar II, King of Yugoslavia's declaration to Serbs, Croats, and Slovenes, draft and clippings, August 1944 (Folder 8: 16)
      - Royal Yugoslavia and the National Committee of Liberation agreement, 1944 (Folder 8: 17)
      - Royal Yugoslav government declaration, circa 1944 (Folder 8: 18)
      - Ivo Cicin ?ain's response to Dr. Ivan ?ubašic, 1944 (Folder 8: 19)
      - Protest note of the Yugoslav political establishment in London, 1945 (Folder 8: 20)
      - Vlado Predavac's report on cooperation with the occupiers, 1946 (Folder 8: 21)
    - Regulations, amendments, and bank reports, circa 1940-1944 (Folder 8)
      - Uredba o Banovini Hrvatske, circa 1940 (Folder 8: 22)
      - Stanje državnog novca kod Federal Reserve Bank, New York, report, 1943 (Folder 8: 23)
      - Uredba sa zakonskom snagom o budžetu Bana Banovine Hrvatske za 1943, 1944 (Folder 8: 24)
      - Izmene i dopune Uredbe sa zaknoskom snagom o preuzimanju Jugoslovenskih trgovackih brodobva od strane Kraljevske Jugoslavenske vlade, 1944 (Folder 8: 25)
      - Rešenje da se sedište Narodne Banke premesti iz Beograda u London, signed by Petar II, King of Yugoslavia, 1944 (Folder 8: 26)
      - Royal Yugoslavia Bank account, transfer from Brazil to the United States, 1944 (Folder 8: 27)
      - Uredba za uredivanje odelenja za štampu Ministarstva inostranih poslova (Folder 8: 28)
    - Telegrams, including news reports and clippings, 1943-1944, 1947 (Folder 8-10)
      - June-July 1943 (Folder 8: 29)
      - August 1943 (Folder 8: 30)
      - September-October 1943 (Folder 8: 31)
      - November 1943 (Folder 8: 32-33)
      - January 1944 (Folder 8: 34)
      - January-March 1944 (Folder 9: 1-7)
      - March-April 1944 (Folder 9: 8-9)
      - April 1944 (Folder 9: 10-11)
      - April-July 1944 (Folder 9: 12)
      - May 1944 (Folder 9: 13-16)
      - May 1944 (Folder 10: 1-2)
      - 1947 (Folder 10: 3)
    - Map of Kraljevina Srba, Hrvata i Slovenaca, undated (Folder 10: 4)
    - Printed matter, 1941-1944 (Folder 10-11)
      - Radio broadcast summary, 1943 (Folder 10: 5)
      - Clippings, press reports and news releases, 1941-1944 (Folder 10)
        - 1941 (Folder 10: 6)
        - June-September 1943 (Folder 10: 7-11)
        - October-November 1944 (Folder 10: 12-13)
        - October-November 1944 (Folder 10: 14-15)
        - 1944 (Folder 10: 16-17)
      - The Nineteenth Century and After, June 1943, June 1944 (Folder 10: 18)
      - Reuters Reports, June-October 1944 (Folder 11: 1-4)
      - Tito Speaks, published by the United South Slavic Committee, London, 1944 (Folder 11: 5)
      - "Maršal Jgoslvije Josip Borz-Tito," by Milovan Ðilas, Bojna I Robcij Klass, June 1944 (Folder 11: 6)
      - Whitehall News, June-October 1944 (Folder 11: 7)
      - Woods and Mountains Yugoslavia, June 1944 (Folder 11: 8)
      - Yugoslav Summary, South East Europe Front, No. 11 and No. 15, 1943 (Folder 11: 9)
      - Miscellany, undated (Folder 11: 10)
    - Telegrams, 1942-1944 (Folder 11-13)
      - May-September 1942 (Folder 11: 11)
      - July-October 1942 (Folder 11: 12-16)
      - November 1942 (Folder 12: 1-2)
      - April-December 1942 (Folder 12: 3-4)
      - September-December 1942 (Folder 12: 5)
      - December 1942-March 1943 (Folder 12: 6)
      - January-June 1943 (Folder 12: 7-14)
      - June-December 1943 (Folder 13: 1-5)
      - Telegrams sent to Draža Mihailović, 1943 (Folder 13: 6)
      - Telegrams from Draža Mihailović, 1943 (Folder 13: 7)
      - Petar II, King of Yugoslavia telegrams to Draža Mihailović, 1943 (Folder 13: 8-9)
      - October 1943-July 1944 (Folder 13: 10-14)
      - January 1945 (Folder 13: 15)
    - Reports, including news and broadcast reports, and clippings, 1941-1943 (Folder 13-14)
      - Tito and Draža Mihailović meetings of 1941. As described by Colonel Bran J. Panticon in, 1952 (Folder 13: 16)
      - "List of Actions by Draža Mihailović's Troops against Germans, Italians, and Bulgarians,", August 1943-April 1944 (Folder 13: 17)
      - "List of Actions by Draža Mihailović's Troops against Partisans,", 1943 (Folder 13: 18)
      - Partisans et Tchetniks, report, by Mladen ?ivkovic, circa 1943 (Folder 13: 19)
        In French.
      - Memorandum No. 450 of the Royal Yugoslavia Government, June 1943 (Folder 13: 20)
      - Draža Mihailović interview, The New York Times, 6 August 1944 (Folder 13: 21)
      - "Mihailovićh," by F.A. Voigt, The Nineteenth Century and After, August 1943 (Folder 13: 22)
      - Draža Mihailović interview transcript, BBC news, 1943 (Folder 13: 23)
      - Yugoslav Information Office reports on Draža Mihailović, 1943 (Folder 13: 24)
      - Clippings, 1943 (Folder 14: 1)
      - Reports, undated (Folder 14: 2)
- Serbian émigré affairs materials, 1947-1977 (Box 14)
  Includes letters, reports, writings, and clippings related to Yugoslav émigré community organizations.
  Arranged by form, then chronologically
  - Puric's Correspondence, 1947-1968 (Folder 14)
    - General, 1947-1957 (Folder 14: 3-5)
    - Serbian Orthodox Church, 1963-1964 (Folder 14: 6)
    - Constantin S. Yoximovic, 1964 (Folder 14: 7)
    - Dr. George Stevan, 1966-1968 (Folder 14: 8)
  - Reports and writings, 1950-1977 (Folder 14)
    - U.S. Council of Foreign Relations on Yugoslavia, 1950 (Folder 14: 9)
    - Rad Sekretarijata centralong narodnog odbora Srpske narodne Odbrane i rad urdništva Sloboda, annual report, 1960-1961 (Folder 14: 10)
    - "Slobodan Yovanovich, Professor, 1869-1958," typescript, Cambridge, 1965 (Folder 14: 11)
    - "Neke pojedinosti o Braci Roš," Politika, 26 November 1972, and Nin, 4 April 1969, includes the court exhibits, and three prints depicting family members, 1965 (Folder 14: 12)
    - Udruženje srpskih pisaca i umetnika u inostranstvu, 1973-1977 (Folder 14: 13)
    - "Da se ne zaboravi, nekoliko podataka iz života naših Saveza," by Branko Peric, typescript, undated (Folder 14: 14)
    - "Srbi i Starcevic," by Adam Pribicevic, typescript, undated (Folder 14: 15)
  - Printed amtter, 1958-1967 (Folder 14)
    - Clippings, 1958 and undated (Folder 14: 16)
    - "Srpski Manastari," Zbornik zaštite Spomenika culture, Knjiga IX, Belgrade, 1958 (Folder 14: 17)
    - Miscellany, 1967 and undated (Folder 14: 18)
- Printed Matter, 1943-1969 (Box 14-15)
  Contains daily newspapers, periodicals, serial issues, and clippings.
  Arranged alphabetically by title, followed by miscellaneous clippings
  - Americaknaski Srbobran, July 1944, August 1968 (Folder 14: 19)
  - Aid for the Yugoslav People-but not for Tito's Dictatorship, by William H. Smith, Munich, 1953 (Folder 14: 20)
  - Branko Perkic, by Pavle Kobac, 1947 (Folder 14: 21)
  - Bulletin, Serbian National-cultural Club of Switzerland, No. 28, 1962, and No. 50, 1968 (Folder 14: 22)
  - Cetnik, 1969 (Folder 14: 23)
  - Documenti o Jugosaviji, "Istina o 25th and 27th Martu," and 27 Mart: "Narodni Ustank ili Zavera protiv Države,", 1951 (Folder 14: 24)
  - Jugoslavia, 1946 (Folder 14: 25)
  - Nša Stvarnost, 1943, 1952-1953 (Folder 14: 26-27)
  - Nša Stvarnost, 1955-1957, 1960 (Folder 15: 1-2)
  - "Ocene i prikazi," by Dr. Vojislav J. Vuckovic, Vojislav J., Yugoslovenska reviaj za medunarodno pravo, VIII, No. 2, 1961 (Folder 15: 3)
  - Poruka, 1950-1959 (Folder 15: 4)
  - Pravoslavlje, August 1968 (Folder 15: 5)
  - Rec Borca, August 1960 (Folder 15: 6)
  - Refelector, May-June 1944 (Folder 15: 7)
  - Savez Zemljoradnika, 1959-1960 (Folder 15: 8)
  - Sloboda, 1955 1960 (Folder 15: 9)
  - Srbima u Hrvatskoj, Sloveniji i Dalmaciji, 1968 (Folder 15: 10)
  - Srpska Zastava, February 1954 (Folder 15: 11)